kramp.com 2018-08-07

# Privacy policy / cookies - KRAMP

**Privacy and cookie statement**

**Privacy**  
Kramp Groep B.V. is responsible for the processing of personal data obtained from visitors through, for example, email, telephone or which we obtain through the use of the website. In this privacy and cookie statement, we explain how we deal with these personal data.

**What personal data do we collect and what do we use it for?**  
We process your personal information for the following purposes:

  * _Delivery of your order_  
For your order, we need your (company) name, email address, address(es), payment details and sometimes your phone number. This information is required to process your order, to keep you informed and to have your order processed as quickly and smoothly as possible.
  * _My account_  
Opening an account on our website requires you to provide some information, including your (company) name, address(es), phone number, email address, delivery and payment details and interests. We store these data in our systems. In addition, we store data from your previous orders so you can easily find them back through your account. We process these personal data to enable and improve your ordering process.
  * _Our customer service_  
To allow our customer service to promptly answer your questions, we use your personal information and make notes of the conversation. These notes of your contact with us are stored to help us answer your question, prepare analyses and improve our services.
  * _Repairs/guarantee/returning goods_  
We offer several services regarding the repair, guarantee and return of our products. To determine whether your product is covered by the guarantee or is eligible for repair, we use your order information and the personal data you provided.
  * _Newsletters_  
If you have given us your prior consent. we will keep you informed of our offers, promotions and our product range via our newsletters. We prepare the newsletters based on your personal data, such as your previous orders and browsing behaviour. This results in a more interesting newsletter for you.
  * _Contests_  
If you participate in a promotion or contest, we will ask you some information, such as your name, address and email address. We also ask for your consent for the processing thereof, possibly by third parties, for the purpose of the promotion/contest and for the preparation of analyses based on the information collected. This allows us to perform the promotion and announce the prize winner(s). It also allows us to measure the response to our advertising measures.
  * _Profiling & personalised ads_  
When you visit our website, we can collect, analyse, and based on your consent, combine personal data of you with your customer number and customer data. This way we can compile a customer profile of you. We divide these customer profiles into a number of categories to analyse your interests and further personalise your offer, such as by showing personalised ads.
  * _Improvement of our website, service and store_  
We are constantly working to improve our services. To achieve this, we or a third party engaged by us may contact you without any obligations to ask you if you would like to participate in a customer or market survey.
  * _Credit check_  
When you become one of our customers and pay on account, we, or a third party on our behalf, may check your creditworthiness. We may also store and process your personal data whenever necessary to prevent abuse or illegal activity on our website. We are obligedto provide this information under, for example, governmental or judicial regulations or when necessary for a legal (criminal) procedure.

**How do we handle the confidentiality of personal data and the disclosure thereof to third parties?**  
We appreciate the trust you have in us and will handle your data with the utmost care. Therefore, we will take appropriate security measures to limit abuse and unauthorised access to your personal data. This way we ensure that only the required persons have access to your data, that data access is secured and that our security measures are checked regularly. In addition, we will, of course, not store your data any longer than necessary to achieve the purposes stated in this privacy and cookie statement.

Furthermore, we will not sell your personal data to third parties. We will only provide your data to third parties with your permission, or when this is necessary to:

  * process your order;
  * answer your questions;
  * offer guarantees and to repair our products;
  * improve our website and/or services;
  * offer promotions and contests as well as the analyses thereof;
  * carry out customer or market surveys;
  * enforce compliance with our terms and conditions;
  * collect invoices.

We will also share your personal data with third parties when this is allowed or required under the law. We reserve the right to share your personal data with our subsidiaries.

Our employees and third parties engaged by us are required to respect the confidentiality of your data, to comply with applicable privacy rules and to properly protect your information. To this end, we have made appropriate arrangements with these third parties. In addition, we only use third parties outside the European Union if these parties provide the same level of protection as required within the European Union.

**Please note:** Our privacy and cookie statement does not apply to third party websites linked to our website. Therefore, we cannot guarantee that these third parties will handle your personal data in a reliable or secure manner. We recommend you read the privacy statements of these third party websites before making use of these websites.

**Cookies**

**How does this website use cookies?**  
On our website, we use cookies or similar technologies that send and save a small text file to your computer, tablet and/or mobile phone when you visit our website. For the ease of reading, all such techniques will be referred to as "cookies".

When visiting the website www.kramp.com, the following cookies are placed:

  1. _Technical or functional cookies_  
These are cookies that are necessary for the website to function. For instance, these cookies ensure that your preferences, such as location and language settings, are remembered and that your products are stored in your online shopping cart when shopping online. According to the cookie law no permission needs to be requested for these cookies.
  2. _Analytics cookies_  
To determine which parts of www.kramp.com are the most interesting to our visitors, we continuously measure how many visitors come to our website and what is most viewed. The recorded information is not traced to persons and is used by us for statistical purposes only. Among other things, this information provides us with insight into the number of visitors on the website and the duration of their visit. This information helps us optimise our website and make it more user-friendly. Before placing these cookies, we ask your permission via our cookie banner.
  3. _Other cookies_  
To enable you to share web pages through social networks, build customer profiles, and personalise newsletters, offers and ads across different channels, we use third-party cookies. Before placing these cookies, we ask your permission via our cookie banner.

**Cookie settings**  
You can select which types of cookies you want to give your permission to. The cookie settings that you select now can be changed at a later date. 

**For which cookies do we ask your permission?**  
The below overview showsthe cookies we use in addition to the technical and functional cookies. Some cookies are used by us, but for other cookies, we use third parties. These parties act on our behalf and we determine what happens with the cookies. There are also cookies that are exclusively placed and used by third parties. We do not control those third parties and how they handle your data. For more information on how these third parties handle cookies, we refer you to the relevant privacy statement. Please note: Third party privacy statements may change regularly.

Cookie name | Purpose of the cookie | Privacy statement link  
---|---|---  
Google Analytics | Information on the collection and analysis of browsing behaviour |  [ Google](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)  
Visual Website Optimizer | A/B testing |  [ Visual Website Optimizer](https://vwo.com/privacy-policy/)  
Usabilla | Requests feedback from customers for improvement purposes |  [ Usabilla](https://usabilla.com/privacy/)  
SnapEngage | Enables the chat function |  [ SnapEngage](https://snapengage.com/privacy-policy/)  
Clang | Shows relevant information in emails |  [ Clang](https://www.e-village.nl/privacy-en-cookiestatement)  
DoubleClick | Shows relevant ads |  [ Google](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)  
Facebook Exchange (FBX) | Shows relevant ads |  [ Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/update)  
Facebook Custom Audience | Ad targeting |  [ Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/update)  
Facebook-pixel | Shows relevant ads |  [ Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/update)  
Google Ads | Measures the use of the website |  [ Google](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)  
Google Adsense | Shows relevant ads |  [ Google](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)  
Google Adservices | Shows relevant ads |  [ Google](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)  
Google AdWords Conversion | Shows relevant ads |  [ Google](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)  
Google Dynamic Remarketing | Shows relevant ads |  [ Google](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)  
Google Tag Manager | To share information on browsing behaviour with third parties |  [ Google](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)  
  
**How can cookies be enabled, disabled and removed?** You can set the browser of your computer in such a manner that you will not receive any cookies during your visit to our website. You can also opt for manually removing cookies before the expiration date of the relevant cookies has expired. To this end, check the settings and the manual of your browser. However, if your browser refuses cookies, it may happen that you cannot use all of our site's features or that you do not have access to certain parts of our website.

**Is it possible for this privacy and cookie statement to be updated?**  
It is not unthinkable that our privacy and cookie policy will be expanded or updated in the near future. We reserve the right to update this privacy and cookie statement. Any changes will be published on this website. You can consult this statement on our website for more information. We recommend checking this statement regularly to ensure you are informed of these changes.

**What to do with complaints about data processing by Kramp Groep B.V.?**  
Of course, we will be happy to help you if you have any complaints about the processing of your personal information. Under privacy legislation, you are entitled to file a complaint against the processing of your personal data. You can file this complaint with the competent regulator of your country.

**How can you contact us to view, change, move or delete your personal data?**  
You are entitled to view, change, move or delete the data we have collected about you. To do this, you can contact us directly by email at sales.nl@kramp.com.

**How can the Kramp Groep B.V. be contacted?**  
If you have any further questions after reading our privacy and cookie statement, please contact us using the contact details below.

Kramp Groep B.V.  
Adress: Breukelaarweg 33, 7051DW, Varsseveld  
Tel + 31-(0)315-254 299  
E-mail: sales.nl@kramp.com  
VAT-nr: NL 0054.35.511.B.03  

_Version September 2017_
